=His Chosen Favor=
=مفضلته المختارة=
(Give me a foothold, and I could move the entire harem)
(أعطني موطئ قدم، وسأتمكن من تحريك الحريم بأكمله)
=Episode 3=
=الحلقة 3=
Prince Rui, halt!
الأمير روي، توقف!
Xiao Yicheng,
شياو ييتشنغ,
why are you holding my consort?
لماذا تحتجز قرينتي؟
Your Majesty.
جلالة الملك.
You returned from the frontier.
لقد عدت من الحدود.
Instead of reporting to me,
بدلاً من تقديم التقارير لي،
you held my consort.
أمسكتَ بقريني.
How utterly improper!
يا له من أمر غير لائق على الإطلاق!
Your consort?
قرينتك؟
I recall she was the late emperor's consort.
أتذكر أنها كانت قرينة الإمبراطور الراحل.
Father is long dead.
لقد توفي أبي منذ زمن طويل.
You're truly audacious!
أنت جريء حقاً!
As the emperor,
بصفته الإمبراطور،
I act as I see fit!
أتصرف كما أراه مناسباً!
What do you think you are?
ماذا تظن نفسك؟
Daring to lecture me!
تجرؤ على إلقاء محاضرة عليّ!
(My son is lecturing me!)
(ابني يلقي عليّ محاضرة!)
Enough!
كافٍ!
Stop arguing!
توقفوا عن الجدال!
Put me down!
أنزلني!
My apologies.
أعتذر.
I'm late.
أنا متأخر.
Not late.
ليس متأخراً.
Nice of you to come.
لطف منك أن تأتي.
You're hurt. What do you want to do?
أنت مصاب. ماذا تريد أن تفعل؟
I'm going to teach
سأقوم بالتدريس
the one who deserves a lesson.
الشخص الذي يستحق درساً.
Consort Xi, apologies.
الملكة شي، أعتذر.
I was waiting for His Majesty to come.
كنت أنتظر قدوم جلالته.
What do you want to do?
ماذا تريد أن تفعل؟
What do I want?
ماذا أريد؟
Of course
بالطبع
to abuse the power and bully you.
لاستغلال السلطة والتنمر عليك.
I dare you!
أتحداكم!
Right now!
الآن!
Kneel and apologize to me!
اركع واعتذر لي!
Outrageous!
أمرٌ شائن!
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
she just used private punishment
لقد استخدمت العقاب الخاص فقط
and forced me prick my hands with silver needles.
وأجبرني على وخز يدي بإبر فضية.
My hands are almost ruined!
يداي تكادان تتلفان!
Look!
ينظر!
Your Majesty, I was only just...
جلالتك، لقد كنت للتو...
You've suffered.
لقد عانيت.
Your Majesty, avenge me!
يا جلالة الملك، انتقم لي!
And Yindan!
و يندان!
She protected me
لقد حمتني
and was nearly tortured to death.
وكاد أن يتعرض للتعذيب حتى الموت.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
Lu Zhen'er was disrespectful to my aunt.
كانت لو تشن إر غير محترمة تجاه عمتي.
- I just tried to warn her. - You lie!
- حاولتُ فقط تحذيرها. - أنتِ تكذبين!
Would I invite you to torture me?
هل أدعوك لتعذيبي؟
The consorts were just fighting over favor.
كانت المحظيات تتنافسن فقط على النفوذ.
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
take Lu Zhen'er and her maid back
خذ Lu Zhen'er وخادمتها
and this matter is over.
وقد انتهى هذا الأمر.
Zhen'er may do
قد تفعل تشن إير ذلك
as she pleases.
كما تشاء.
Xiao Wenjing.
شياو ون جينغ.
Let it go.
دع الأمر يمر.
Come.
يأتي.
Are you alright?
هل أنت بخير؟
(So many old scars.)
(ندوب قديمة كثيرة.)
Guards!
حراس!
Guards, quickly!
أيها الحراس، بسرعة!
Lu Zhen'er!
لو زينير!
Save me, Aunt!
أنقذيني يا عمتي!
Guards!
حراس!
Aunt!
عمة!
Stop!
قف!
I also have a powerful backing!
لديّ أيضاً دعم قوي!
As Her Majesty said,
كما قالت جلالتها،
it was just fighting for favor.
كان الأمر مجرد صراع من أجل الحصول على امتيازات.
Can't be considered audacious.
لا يمكن اعتبار ذلك جريئاً.
Yindan,
من يين،
let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Go!
يذهب!
Place your hands on my shoulders
ضع يديك على كتفيّ
and it hurts less now?
وهل أصبح الألم أقل الآن؟
Give me a foothold,
أعطني موطئ قدم،
and I could move the entire harem.
وبإمكاني نقل الحريم بأكمله.
Consort Xi knew I would be inspecting the military camp today,
كانت الملكة شي تعلم أنني سأقوم بتفقد المعسكر العسكري اليوم،
so she seized the chance to act against you.
لذا انتهزت الفرصة للتصرف ضدك.
That isn't your fault.
هذا ليس خطأك.
You can't be by my side day and night.
لا يمكنك أن تبقى بجانبي ليلاً ونهاراً.
Blame myself.
ألوم نفسي.
I have no power
ليس لدي أي قوة
or influence,
أو التأثير،
so I'm at the mercy of others.
لذا فأنا تحت رحمة الآخرين.
What should we do?
ماذا ينبغي علينا أن نفعل؟
Get me a Bodhisattva statue.
أحضر لي تمثالاً لبوديساتفا.
What?
ماذا؟
My luck has been terrible lately.
لقد كان حظي سيئاً للغاية مؤخراً.
I desperately need to pray.
أنا في أمس الحاجة إلى الصلاة.
Will that help?
هل سيساعد ذلك؟
Of course!
بالطبع!
When all else fails,
عندما تفشل كل المحاولات الأخرى،
trust in metaphysics!
الثقة في الميتافيزيقا!
Go to Chenghua Temple.
اذهب إلى معبد تشنغهوا.
Its Bodhisattva is very efficacious.
إن بوديساتفا الخاص به فعال للغاية.
Really?
حقًا؟
Then I'll go tomorrow.
سأذهب غداً إذاً.
Your Majesty!
جلالتك!
Lu Zhen'er has gone too far!
لقد تجاوزت لو تشن إير الحد!
Look what she's done to me.
انظر ماذا فعلت بي.
You weren't ruthless enough,
لم تكن قاسياً بما فيه الكفاية،
so you couldn't defeat her.
إذن لم تستطع هزيمتها.
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
you shielded her at every turn,
لقد حميتها في كل منعطف،
so I have ended up like this.
وهكذا انتهى بي المطاف على هذا النحو.
When have I ever shielded her?
متى قمت بحمايتها؟
Earlier at Yonghe Palace,
في وقت سابق في قصر يونغهي،
and again today in her palace,
ومرة أخرى اليوم في قصرها،
you always shielded her.
كنت تحميها دائماً.
I've never shielded her.
لم أقم بحمايتها قط.
You're soft-hearted
أنت رقيق القلب
and let her escape every time.
ودعها تهرب في كل مرة.
Then,
ثم،
what should I do?
ماذا علي أن أفعل؟
She's going to Chenghua Temple tomorrow.
ستذهب إلى معبد تشنغوا غداً.
I want her to never see
أريدها ألا ترى أبداً
the sun the day after tomorrow.
الشمس بعد غد.
Yindan, what are they doing?
يندان، ماذا يفعلون؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
they probably found out in advance
ربما اكتشفوا ذلك مسبقاً
that His Majesty would pass by,
أن جلالته سيمر من هنا،
so they're dancing here,
إذن فهم يرقصون هنا،
waiting for His Majesty.
في انتظار جلالته.
If they can gain His Majesty's favor,
إذا استطاعوا أن يحظوا برضا جلالته،
they can rise up.
بإمكانهم النهوض.
Seems the people under Consort Xi
يبدو أن الناس تحت حكم الملكة شي
aren't all that loyal after all.
ليسوا مخلصين إلى هذا الحد في نهاية المطاف.
Let's go.
دعنا نذهب.
Bodhisattva,
بوديساتفا،
I ask not for a shred of true love,
لا أطلب ذرة من الحب الحقيقي،
only for great wealth, honor, peace and safety.
فقط من أجل الثروة العظيمة والشرف والسلام والأمان.
And bless my sister
بارك الله في أختي
to be happy every day,
أن تكون سعيداً كل يوم،
safe and free from worry.
آمن وخالٍ من القلق.
Why did you stop?
لماذا توقفت؟
Zisu,
زيسو،
you were dancing happily in the imperial garden.
كنت ترقص بسعادة في الحديقة الإمبراطورية.
Why aren't you dancing now?
لماذا لا ترقص الآن؟
Your Highness, the snow is falling heavily.
يا صاحب السمو، الثلج يتساقط بغزارة.
Perhaps you should return to the palace.
ربما ينبغي عليك العودة إلى القصر.
Or it may harm your health.
أو قد يضر بصحتك.
No rush. The person I'm waiting for
لا داعي للعجلة. الشخص الذي أنتظره
hasn't arrived yet.
لم يصل بعد.
Yes.
نعم.
Sis, the snow is really heavy today.
يا أختي، الثلج كثيف جداً اليوم.
Your Highness.
صاحب السمو.
Guards!
حراس!
Summon Consort Lu.
استدعاء القرينة لو.
- Yes.
- نعم.
Go to His Majesty.
اذهب إلى جلالته.
Get him to save me!
اجعله ينقذني!
Okay.
تمام.
Let go of me!
اتركني!
Who is this?
من هذا؟
Let me have a good look.
دعني ألقي نظرة جيدة.
Oh, His Majesty's most beloved Consort Lu.
يا لو، قرينة جلالته المحبوبة.
Why are you in such a sorry state today?
لماذا أنت في هذه الحالة المزرية اليوم؟
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
aren't you afraid
ألا تخاف؟
His Majesty will be furious?
هل سيغضب جلالته؟
Do you think gaining His Majesty's favor
هل تعتقد أن نيل رضا جلالته أمرٌ ممكن؟
means you can challenge me?
هل هذا يعني أنه يمكنك تحدّي؟
Don't know the rules, huh?
ألا تعرف القواعد؟
Today, I'll teach you
اليوم، سأعلمك
what rules mean.
ما معنى القواعد؟
Kneel!
اركع!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Let go of me!
اتركني!
If you kill me,
إذا قتلتني،
His Majesty won't forgive you.
لن يغفر لك جلالته.
Seems she is out of her mind.
يبدو أنها فقدت عقلها.
Guards.
حراس.
Help her clear her mind.
ساعدها على تصفية ذهنها.
You all saw it.
لقد رأيتموه جميعاً.
She plunged into the vat herself.
انغمست بنفسها في الحوض.
I had nothing to do with it.
لم يكن لي أي علاقة بالأمر.
Your eyes
عيناك
are indeed very beautiful.
إنها جميلة جداً بالفعل.
But I simply can't stand beautiful things.
لكنني ببساطة لا أطيق الأشياء الجميلة.
Yanyu,
لك،
dig out her eyes
اقتلعي عينيها
and feed them to the dogs.
وأطعمها للكلاب.
Yes.
نعم.
Get off!
ترجل!
What are you doing?
ماذا تفعل؟
Release Her Highness.
أطلقوا سراح صاحبة السمو.
So you fear too?
إذن أنت خائف أيضاً؟
Lu Zhen'er!
لو زينير!
If you dare lay a finger on me,
إن تجرأت على أن تمسني،
my aunt will have your skin flayed!
ستأمر عمتي بسلخ جلدك!
I can flay your skin right now.
بإمكاني سلخ جلدك الآن.
Make an incision here
قم بعمل شق هنا
and pour mercury in.
ثم صب الزئبق فيه.
Then I'll get a complete human skin.
ثم سأحصل على جلد بشري كامل.
Your Highness,
صاحب السمو،
would you like to give it a try?
هل ترغب في تجربته؟
Y-You wouldn't dare!
لن تجرؤ!
You even dared to dig out my eyes.
بل إنك تجرأت على فقء عيني.
What wouldn't I dare?
ما الذي لا أجرؤ على فعله؟
Lu Zhen'er, calm down.
لو Zhen'er، اهدأ.
I was just trying to scare you.
كنت أحاول فقط أن أخيفك.
I can give you whatever you want.
أستطيع أن أعطيك كل ما تريد.
Don't kill me.
لا تقتلني.
In the dead of winter,
في أوج الشتاء،
why are they dancing by the palace path?
لماذا يرقصون على طريق القصر؟
Maybe a consort
ربما قرين
hearing that His Majesty would pass by,
عندما علمت أن جلالته سيمرّ من هنا،
so she deliberately waited here,
لذا فقد انتظرت هنا عن قصد،
trying to win some favor.
محاولة لكسب بعض الود.
Let's go
دعنا نذهب
take a look.
ألقِ نظرة.
Go.
يذهب.
Which palace are they from?
من أي قصر هم؟
This isn't about winning favor.
الأمر لا يتعلق بكسب التأييد.
Clearly, they've offended that one.
من الواضح أنهم أساءوا إلى ذلك الشخص.
You mean
تقصد
Consort Xi?
القرينة شي؟
Stop.
قف.
Asking for death?
هل تطلب الموت؟
Do you think
هل تعتقد
this drum looks strange?
هل تبدو هذه الطبلة غريبة؟
It's Consort Xi!
إنها القرينة شي!
Consort Xi.
القرينة شي.
You're awake.
أنت مستيقظ.
What happened to me?
ماذا حدث لي؟
Yindan asked me to save you.
طلب مني يندان أن أنقذك.
When I rushed over,
عندما هرعت إلى هناك،
I saw you passed out in the imperial garden.
رأيتك فاقداً للوعي في الحديقة الإمبراطورية.
What exactly happened?
ما الذي حدث بالضبط؟
You were beaten.
لقد تعرضت للضرب.
Consort Xi again.
قرينة شي مرة أخرى.
Her Majesty is here.
جلالتها هنا.
You wretch!
يا لك من بائس!
You actually killed Xi'er.
لقد قتلت شي إير بالفعل.
So you did kill her.
إذن أنت قتلتها.
I didn't kill anyone.
لم أقتل أحداً.
How dare you argue!
كيف تجرؤ على الجدال!
Jingxi, slap her mouth until it's broken!
جينغشي، اصفعي فمها حتى ينكسر!
Wait!
انتظر!
Listen to me.
استمع لي.
I swear I did not kill Consort Xi.
أقسم أنني لم أقتل الزوجة شي.
Don't wrong me.
لا تظلمني.
Mother,
الأم،
don't pin such a charge casually!
لا توجه مثل هذه التهمة باستخفاف!
Any evidence?
هل من دليل؟
You want evidence?
هل تريد دليلاً؟
Then I'll show you.
سأريك ذلك.
So that you won't say I wronged her.
حتى لا تقولي إني ظلمتها.
Consort Lu, if you didn't kill Xi'er,
يا قرينة لو، إن لم تكوني قد قتلتِ شي إير،
why was your gold hairpin
لماذا كان دبوس شعرك الذهبي؟
found on her body?
عُثر عليه على جسدها؟
Your Majesty,
جلالة الملك،
I did see her yesterday.
لقد رأيتها بالأمس.
But
لكن
she called me over to beat me.
لقد نادتني لتضربني.
I swear I didn't kill her.
أقسم أنني لم أقتلها.
If you wrong me,
إذا أخطأت في حقي،
the murderer will escape justice.
سيفلت القاتل من العقاب.
So,
لذا،
give me one day.
أعطني يوماً واحداً.
I can prove my innocence.
أستطيع إثبات براءتي.
What if you can't?
ماذا لو لم تستطع؟
I'll personally slice her 3,000 times
سأقوم شخصياً بتقطيعها إلى 3000 قطعة
to give you justice.
لتحقيق العدالة لكم.
It's all your fault.
كل هذا خطأك.
If you hadn't shielded her,
لو لم تكن قد حميتها،
Xi'er wouldn't have died.
لم تكن شي إير لتموت.
She's dead, so what?
لقد ماتت، وماذا في ذلك؟
She killed so many people.
لقد قتلت الكثير من الناس.
Now it's just retribution.
الآن الأمر مجرد انتقام.
Insolent!
وقح!
Lu Zhen'er must die today.
يجب أن يموت لو زينير اليوم.
Guards!
حراس!
Yes.
نعم.
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
help me. I didn't kill anyone.
ساعدني. لم أقتل أحداً.
I have to take care of my sister.
عليّ أن أعتني بأختي.
I finally found her.
لقد وجدتها أخيراً.
I can't die for no reason.
لا يمكنني أن أموت بلا سبب.
Xiao Wenjing, I didn't kill anyone.
شياو وينجينغ، لم أقتل أحداً.
Halt!
وقف!
(Lu Zhen'er,)
(لو زينير،)
(I do want to kill you,)
(أريد قتلك فعلاً،)
(but not today.)
(لكن ليس اليوم.)
Mother,
الأم،
you can't kill her today.
لا يمكنك قتلها اليوم.
What if I insist?
ماذا لو أصررتُ؟
I said no,
قلت لا،
so you can't.
لذا لا يمكنك ذلك.
Xiao Wenjing,
شياو ون جينغ
are you defying me to the bitter end?
هل ستتحداني حتى النهاية المريرة؟
If you wish to protect her,
إذا كنت ترغب في حمايتها،
there will be a price.
سيكون هناك ثمن.
♪Moonlight beyond the pass sighs for restless fluttering petals♪
ضوء القمر وراء الممر يتنهد لبتلات الزهور المتراقصة المضطربة.
♪Life is fleeting, spring rivers turn cold♪
الحياة زائلة، وأنهار الربيع تبرد.
♪Clear boat, misty waters frost again, shore willows hasten yellow♪
قارب صافٍ، مياه ضبابية تتجمد من جديد، وأشجار الصفصاف على الشاطئ تسرع في اصفرارها.
♪Sitting alone by the window, watching the mournful sunset♪
جالسًا وحيدًا بجوار النافذة، يشاهد غروب الشمس الحزين.
♪In the courtyard's music room, wind recounts the past♪
في غرفة الموسيقى بالفناء، تروي الرياح الماضي.
♪Empty lanes still sing of childhood days♪
الشوارع الخالية لا تزال تحكي عن أيام الطفولة.
♪On stage, I mimic your songs, entrusting thoughts to recklessness♪
على المسرح، أقلد أغنياتك، وأترك ​​أفكاري للتهور.
♪Where is my love today♪
أين حبي اليوم؟
♪I ponder whom to gaze upon, a thousand green hills frosted white♪
أتأمل فيمن أنظر، ألف تلة خضراء مغطاة بالصقيع الأبيض؟
♪Awaiting crabapple blossoms, a fleeting dream♪
في انتظار أزهار التفاح البري، حلم عابر.
♪I ponder whom to share a toast with, let life laugh at my folly♪
أتساءل مع من أرفع نخبًا، دع الحياة تسخر من حماقتي.
♪Those lost within the play are the most insane♪
أولئك الذين تاهوا في المسرحية هم الأكثر جنوناً.
♪In the courtyard's music room, wind recounts the past♪
في غرفة الموسيقى بالفناء، تروي الرياح الماضي.
♪Empty lanes still sing of childhood days♪
الشوارع الخالية لا تزال تحكي عن أيام الطفولة.
♪On stage, I mimic your songs, entrusting thoughts to recklessness♪
على المسرح، أقلد أغنياتك، وأترك ​​أفكاري للتهور.
♪Where is my love today♪
أين حبي اليوم؟
♪I ponder whom to share a toast with, let life laugh at my folly♪
أتساءل مع من أرفع نخبًا، دع الحياة تسخر من حماقتي.
♪Those lost within the play are the most insane♪
أولئك الذين تاهوا في المسرحية هم الأكثر جنوناً.
♪Only then knowing this life's yearning is the deepest folly♪
???عندها فقط يصبح إدراك أن هذا الشوق في الحياة هو أعمق حماقة؟